<resources>
    <string name="app_name">DengueMaster</string>
    <string name="potential_breeding_sites">   POTENTIAL BREEDING SITES  </string>
    <string name="description">The dengue vectors, are container breeders; they breed in a wide variety of artificial and natural wet containers/receptacles, preferably with dark coloured surfaces and holding clear (unpolluted) water.

Dengue vector breeding sites are found within and outside houses/premises, at ground level as well as above ground level in places such as roof gutters, overhead tanks and receptacles on slabs, and in small and large containers (Example: old tyres placed on roofs) These containers are found at any type of premises including houses, offices, hospitals, garages, commercial sites, yards containing automobile parts, schools, religious places, cemeteries, bare lands, construction sites and plant nurseries. Furthermore, water holding discarded containers along river and stream banks, railway lines are also possible breeding sites of Ae. aegypti and Ae. albopictus. However, in some instances, the breeding sites are area specific (Example: shallow cemented wells in Batticaloa and Jaffna). Ae. aegypti prefers to oviposit in artificial containers. This species is a skip ovipositor, thus, a single female mosquito lays eggs in a number of containers in a single oviposition cycle. Although Ae. albopictus is considered as a sylvatic species and breeds in natural containers such as leaf axils and tree holes, it also breeds in artificial containers in urban and peri-urban areas. Ae. aegypti shares its habitat with other Aedes species including Ae. albopictus, non Aedes species and occasionally with some Anopheles species.

The most common breeding sites of Ae. aegypti and Ae. albopictus in Sri Lanka can be classified broadly into:

Discarded receptacles (plastic containers, tins, clay pots, yoghurt and ice cream cups, bottles, cans, damaged ceramic items, coconut shells etc.)
Water storage containers (water storage cement tanks, barrels and other containers)
Automobile tyres and machinery parts
Building structures (roof gutters, concrete slabs etc.)
Household /institutional appliances (refrigerator trays, flower vases, ornamental ponds, non-functional cisterns and squatting pans of wash rooms)
Other artificial breeding sites (abandoned boats, cemeteries etc)
Natural breeding sites (leaf axils, tree holes)
INDOOR AND OUTDOOR BREEDING SITES OF DENGUE VECTORS
Dengue vectors breeding sites are found both indoors and outdoors. Some of the common indoor and outdoor breeding sites of Ae. aegypti and Ae. albopictus are mentioned below.

Common indoor breeding sites
Refrigerator trays
Flower vases
Ornamental ponds
Water storage tanks/ containers in the toilets, bathrooms, kitchens etc.
Non functioning cisterns and squatting pans of toilets
Ant traps
Abandoned fish tanks
Lift wells in partly constructed buildings
Common outdoor breeding sites
Discarded containers (Ground level and on concrete slabs)
Water storage tanks and barrels
Shallow cemented wells and manhole service pits
Ornamental ponds
Tyres
Flower pots
Bamboo stumps
Coconut shells
Roof gutters</string>
    <string name="prevent_descriptionn">HOW TO PROTECT YOURSELF FROM GETTING DENGUE FEVER
Prevention is also based on protection against mosquito bites. Aedes mosquitoes show diurnal biting activities in both indoor and outdoor environments. Therefore, personal protective measures should be applied all day long and especially during the hours of highest mosquito activity (mid-morning and late afternoon).

Personal protective measures to avoid mosquito bites should be applied when staying in dengue risk areas.

Using physical barriers such as Screening doors and windows of premises using mosquito proof meshes.
Protective clothes to cover the body specially for children those who do outdoor activities in the mornings and afternoons.
Application of natural repellents such as citronella oil, lemon grass oil, neem oil and chemical repellents containing DEET (N,N-Diethyl-m-toluamide). However, effects of repellents are short term. (½- 6 hours)
Repellent use must be strictly done in accordance with the instructions indicated on the product label.
Dengue transmission is predominantly seen in urban areas, usually as family or immediate neighbourhood groups of patients (Clusters). Therefore, if a member of the family or anyone in the immediate neighbourhood is ill with dengue such patients and others should be protected from mosquito bites.

Travellers, especially children, pregnant women, and people with immune disorders or severe chronic illnesses, should consult their doctor or seek advice from a travel clinic to receive personalized recommendations on use of repellents and protection before travelling

Similar protective measures apply to symptomatic patients in order to prevent the disease from being transmitted to non-infected mosquitoes. </string>
    <string name="prevnt">HOW TO PREVENT</string>
    <string name="REP">REGISTERED MOSQUITO REPELLENTS</string>
    <string name="REP_descriptionn">Given below is a list of chemicals that are registered under the Registrar of Pesticides that can be used as effective mosquito repellents.

<br>mosquito repellents:\n </br><br>
            Mino 8:Ethylbutyl acetylaminopropionate 80g/L\n </br><br>
Sofell:N, N-diethyl-m-toluamide 13%\n </br><br>
Sofell Spray:N, N-diethyl-m-toluamide 13%\n </br><br>
Moso:Icaridin 20%(w/w)\n </br></string>
    <string name="social_descriptionn">Social mobilization enhances community participation for sustainable Dengue Fever / Dengue Haemorrhagic Fever control and prevention programmes.

Activities include :

Declaration of Mosquito Control Weeks and media seminars.
Production of Information, Education and Communication (IEC) materials.
Advertising campaigns through electronic and print media to create awareness among public on control / prevention strategies and to promote health seeking behavior.
COMMUNICATION FOR BEHAVIOURAL IMPACT
The strategies for the prevention and control of dengue include prompt diagnosis of fever cases, management or elimination of larval habitats in and around homes, work settings, schools, etc, and reducing human vector contacts.

Communication for behavioural impact (COMBI), espoused by WHO, is an innovative approach to fill this gap to mobilize individual and family action, utilizing social mobilization and communication to bring measurable changes in behavior. It helps to plan, implement and monitor a variety of communication actions intended to engage individuals for adoption of healthy behaviours.

COMBI objectives include the clear identification of the target audience, a detailed description of the behaviour being promoted and the frequency of the behaviour, the measurable impact that is desired over a specific time period. In other words, the objectives should be ‘SMART’ (specific, measurable, appropriate, realistic, time-bound).

Specific: who or what is the focus; what change(s) are intended.
Measurable: specified quantum (e.g. % change intended).
Appropriate: based on target needs and aimed at specific health-related benefits.
Realistic: can be reasonably achieved.
Time-bound: specific time period to realize the objectives.
COMBI thus entails purposive and tailor-made strategic communication solutions intended to engage a specific target audience into responsive action.

In developing the preliminary objectives, suitable recommendations for action by different segments should be considered.

Whose behaviour should be changed to bring about the desired outcomes? Who is the target audience?
What is required to be done? Is it feasible? Is it effective?
Why are they not doing it now? What are the barriers and motivators?
What activities can address the factors most influential to change behaviour?
Are materials/products/services needed to support those activities? If yes, are those easily available? If not, what should be done?
The behavioural objectives, target groups and key messages currently used are stated below:

Behavioural objectives and target groups:
To prompt housewives in 80-90% of homes in MOH areas to remove dengue breeding sites in their houses and surroundings at least once a week.
To prompt principals and teachers in 80-90% of schools to keep their school premises   free of dengue breeding sites through regular inspections every Monday and Thursday.
To establish “Dengue Prevention Committees” in all government institutions to inspect and remove dengue breeding sites in their premises and surroundings at least once a week.
To motivate patients with fever for more than 02 days to seek treatment from a qualified doctor
Key messages:
Every Sunday for 30 minutes, inspect your house and surrounding for dengue breeding sites. Remove or destroy them.
Every Friday for 30 minutes, inspect your school premises for dengue breeding sites. Remove or destroy them.
Seek treatment from a qualified doctor, if you have fever for more than 02 days.
Do not take pain killers/ anti-inflammatory drugs, if you have fever.
ENFORCEMENT OF LAW AGAINST OFFENDERS
Enforcement of law against the offenders who are keeping dengue mosquito breeding places in his/her premises which will endanger the lives of others.

A major obstacle to effective implementation of selective/ integrated mosquito control has been the inability to achieve and sustain expected desired behaviour. Despite growing levels of knowledge and awareness about dengue and mosquitoes, adopting and maintaining effective and feasible new behaviour which remains a challenge.

SPECIAL TARGET GROUPS
1. Mosquito Control in Construction Sites
Check for mosquito breeding in the following places:

Discarded receptacles and building wastes in the worksite and site offices
Building materials, canvas sheets, equipment and machinery
Puddles on the concrete floors of all upper levels and basements
Water storage drums, tanks and containers
Bulk waste containers
Lift wells
Safety barriers
Rooftops and water tanks
Treatment plants
Any other water-bearing receptacles
Destruction of mosquito breeding sites
Destroy/ eliminate all mosquito breeding sites found during the inspection.

Report to the construction site supervisor and the head of the institution of the relevant authority all the breeding detected and the potential breeding habitats observed so that appropriate interim or permanent measures can be taken to eliminate the potential breeding grounds.

Fogging
It is not mandatory to conduct fogging at construction sites. Fogging treatment should only be done when there is an impending disease outbreak or epidemic situations in the area.

Given below is a list of selected larvicides for general use


General name	Products register under ROP
Bacillus thuringiensis var israelensis serotype H-14	Bacto Bti, Bactivec, Mosquito Dunk
Pyriproxyfen	Sumilarv 0.5 G
Novaluron	Rimon®10 EC
Polydimethylsiloxane	Aquatain AMF
Links to Formats
Monthly Inspection Summary for Construction Sites
Construction Site Weekly Inspection Format
ROP Circular
2. Prevention of mosquito breeding places in schools and education institutes
Recent entomological surveys and routine school inspection programmes conducted by health teams detected that 60% of the schools have potential for dengue breeding habitats. Ministry of Education is one of the main responsible ministries in Presidential Task Force. It has been given a mandate to engage all schools and higher education institutes to conduct clean –up campaigns.

Activities conducted in schools
Establishment of dengue committees in schools.
Dividing the school environment to different zones and giving the responsibility of each zone to different class rooms.
Allocation of one hour on a selected day per week to remove mosquito breeding sites with the participation of all teachers and students (e.g. Friday morning from 11.00am to 12.00 noon).
Inspection of the school premises weekly by the school dengue committee and provision of a report weekly to the Principal.
Carrying out the above mosquito control measures at the school hostels or boarding houses, vacant school buildings and construction sites in schools.
Development of proper waste management systems in schools/higher education centers.
All Principals should submit a monthly report to the Zonal Director and to the relevant MOH.
Have a proper plan to conduct clean up campaigns before and during the school vacations and just before the school starts.
Maintaining a fever register for school children.
Check for mosquito breeding in the following places within school premises
Discarded receptacles in open areas and under bushes in school premises
Open and closed drains
Manholes
Cement lined ground ponds
Tree holes, bamboo stumps and leaf axil
Refuse bins and bin covers, especially when unused
Scupper drains in common corridors
Flower pots, plant pots and saucers and other ornamental structures
Air-conditioner trays
Unused equipments and other items for e.g. canvas sheets, dustpans, tyres, broken plastic chairs etc at storage areas
Cement rooftops and roof gutters
Water storage tanks
Unused/ broken cisterns and bowls of toilets
Any other water-bearing receptacles
Following measures can be taken to eliminate mosquito breeding in the school premises during the inspection
Ensure the water storage tanks are properly covered and all drainage outlets are sealed
Collect and burn, bury or dispose the discarded containers properly
Use larvivorous fish in ground level water storage tanks
Discourage planting of water holding plants in its axils
Take immediate action to remove unwanted stored (inventory) items
Clean blocked roof gutters
Report to the school management committee of all the breeding sites detected and the potential breeding habitats observed, so that appropriate interim or permanent measures can be taken to eliminate the potential breeding grounds.
Links to
Dengue Free Child App
School Inspection card</string>
    <string name="social">SOCIAL MOBILIZATION </string>
    <string name="map_key" />
    <string name="title_activity_maplocation">maplocation</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">MapsActivity</string>

    <string name="default_info_title">Default Location</string>
    <string name="default_info_snippet">No places found, because location permission is disabled.</string>
    <string name="pick_place">Choose a place</string>
    <string name="option_get_place">Get place</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps2">MapsActivity2</string>
    <string name="contactus"><![CDATA[Title\tEmail Municipal Commissioner\tcommissioner@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Municipal Commissioner (Engineering Services)\tdepcomeng@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Municipal Commissioner (Administration)\tdmcadmin@colombo.mc.gov.lk Municipal Secretary\tsecretary@colombo.mc.gov.lk Municipal Treasurer\ttreasurer@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief Medical Officer of Health\tcmoh@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief Municipal Veterinary Surgeon\tcmvs@colombo.mc.gov.lk Municipal Assessor\tassessor@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief Librarian\tclibrarian@colombo.mc.gov.lk Director Playground & Recreation Department\tdirprd@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief Ayurvedic Medical Officer\tcamo@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief Dispensary Medical Officer\tcdmo@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief Legal Officer\tclegoff@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief Procurement Manager\tcprocmgr@colombo.mc.gov.lk Director of Training\tdirtraining@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief Fire Officer\tcfo@colombo.mc.gov.lk Director Engineering (TDRS)\tdirtdrs@colombo.mc.gov.lk Director Engineering (Development)\tdirdev@colombo.mc.gov.lk Director Engineering (LED)\tdirled@colombo.mc.gov.lk Director Engineering (Projects)\tdirproj@colombo.mc.gov.lk Director Engineering (SWM)\tdirswm@colombo.mc.gov.lk Director (City Planning)\tdircp@colombo.mc.gov.lk Director Engineering (Works)\tdirworks@colombo.mc.gov.lk Director Engineering(Workshop)\tdirworkshop@colombo.mc.gov.lk Director Engineering (Drainage and Water Supply)\tdirdws@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Municipal Treasurer (Finance & Administration)\tdtfa@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Municipal Treasurer (Revenue)\tdtrev@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Municipal Treasurer (Information Technology and Central Accounts)\tdtitca@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Chief Municipal Veterinary Surgeon\tdcmvs@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Chief Municipal Veterinary Surgeon\tdcmvs2@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Chief Medical Officer of Health(Environmental Health Sanitation)\tdcmohenv@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Chief Medical Officer of Health(Laboratory Services, City Microbiologist)\tdcmohlab@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Chief Medical Officer of Health(Maternity and Child Health)\tdcmohmat@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Municipal Assessor\tdepasses@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Municipal Assessor\tdepasses2@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Chief Librarian\tdepclib@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Planning & Studies)\tddpls@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Traffic & Road Design)\tddtraffic@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Designs)\tdddesigns@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Constructions)\tddconst@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Constructions)\tddconst2@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering Solid Waste Management (South)\tddswms@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Land and Environmental Development)\tddled@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Planning)\tddplan@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Works-North)\tddwnorth@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Works-South)\tddwsouth@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Works)\tddworks@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering\tdd@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Materials Laboratory)\tddmat@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Production)\tddpro@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Electrical)\tddelec@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Drainage)\tdddrain@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Water Supply)\tddws@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Drainage Design)\tdddraind@colombo.mc.gov.lk Deputy Director Engineering (Pumping Station)\tddps@colombo.mc.gov.lk Project Director\tprojdir@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief District Engineer – District Office No. 01\tcde1@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief District Engineer – District Office No. 02 A\tcde2a@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief District Engineer – District Office No. 02 B\tcde2b@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief District Engineer – District Office No. 03\tcde3@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief District Engineer – District Office No. 04\tcde4@colombo.mc.gov.lk Chief District Engineer – District Office No. 05\tcde5@colombo.mc.gov.lk Medical Officer of Health – District Office No.01\tmoh1@colombo.mc.gov.lk Medical Officer of Health – District Office No.02 A\tmoh2a@colombo.mc.gov.lk Medical Officer of Health – District Office No.02 B\tmoh2b@colombo.mc.gov.lk Medical Officer of Health – District Office No.03\tmoh3@colombo.mc.gov.lk Medical Officer of Health – District Office No.04\tmoh4@colombo.mc.gov.lk Medical Officer of Health – District Office No.05\tmoh5@colombo.mc.gov.lk]]></string>
    <string name="municipal_council">Town Hall, Colombo 07<br> munici@slt.lk \n </br>
        <br>(011) 2684290\n </br></string>
    <string name="ndcu">National Dengue Control Unit
Public Health Complex<br>
555/5, Elvitigala Mawatha,
Narahenpita, Colombo 05 \n </br>
       <br> ndcu2010@yahoo.com \n </br>
        <br> +94-112368416 \n </br>
<br>+94-112369893 \n </br>
    </string>
    <string name="intro_app_name" ><br>Welcome to \n </br><br> The DMaster \n </br></string>

</resources>